

TOMAS PEREZ WEB DEVELOPER & DESIGNER

- 404-788-8336
- ✓ tomaspz@gmail.com
- www.weblocomotion.com

Web Development & Design

This letter is to express my interest in the job posted on your website.

After many years working in the field as a freelance, self taught web developer and designer, I decided to obtain my professional certification from the W3C as a front-end web developer. My freelance work creating websites using open source frameworks like Joomla, Wordpress, Drupal and Magento also allowed me the freedom to actively participate in raising my three boys.

Now, that my children are nearly grown and creating experiences of their own, I wish to take my career to the next level and create state-of-the-art, user-friendly websites and applications as part of a team. Working alone is an unbelievable adventure and I have learned a lot, but it also makes clear what the advantages would be to have a team of intelligent, motivated colleagues. I am confident I would be an excellent addition to your organization.

I have a B.S. degree in Chemical Engineering, but I have found that web and design are more suited to my skills. In addition to my knowledge base, I love to learn about new technologies. It is very important to me to stay up-to-date on industry trends and advancements. I am eager to enter this new phase of my career and my life, which will put me ahead of the curve and allow me to deliver exceptional work.

I've attached a copy of my resume detailing my education and experience.

Sincerly yours,

7omás Pérez

Tomás Pérez



TOMAS PEREZ WEB DEVELOPER & DESIGNER

Cell: 404-788-8336

www.weblocomotion.com

Skills

HTML5 CSS3 Javascript
Java C++ Python
XAMP Joomla! JSON
Angular 6 React Nodejs

MySQL MongoDB

Photoshop Illustrator Acrobat

Resourceful

Easygoing

Positive

Problem Solving

Great Actitud

References

Available upon request

Objective

I am looking for a position in front-end web development with web technologies such as Angularjs, Reactjs, JQuery and other libraries and frameworks. After obtaining my professional certification from the World Wide Web Consortium, I am eager to work in the field with a team of like minded professionals and bring value to the team.

Experience

Owner - Web Locomotion LLC.

I have been working creating websites with open source content management systems like Joomla, Wordpress, Drupal and Magento. I am familiar with the XAMP stack and web design in general using Adobe products (Photoshop, Illustrator, Acrobat, etc).

O 2002 - present Freelance IT and Web Design

Since I have been a staty-at-home dad, I have been working as a freelance doing IT consulting and web development in general. The exponential growth of the web made me realize the opportunity that web technologies could offer.

O 1998 - 2002 **Network Engineer.**

2000 - 2002 TRG Networking, Baltimore, MD

1998 - 2000 Management Works, Baltimore, MD

Education

O 2018 - edx.org

W3C Certified Professional Front-End Web Developer

CSS Basics

HTML5 and CSS Fundamentals

HTML5 Coding Essentials and Best Practices

Javascript Introduction
HTML5 Apps and Games

O 2018 - edx.org

Microsoft AngularJS: Framework Fundamentals

O 2017 - Kennesaw State University

CS5000 Foundations of Programming in Java
CS5020 Computer Architecture and OSs

O 2016 - edx.org

MITx Introduction to CS and Programming with Python

O 1993 - Universidad Politécnica de Catalunya (Polytechnic University of Catalonia)

UPC Ingeniero Técnico Industrial Químico (Chemical Engineering)

Equivalent to Level 6 EQF (European Qualification Framework)

Equivalent to Bachelor of Science Degree in the USA



TOMAS PEREZ WEB DEVELOPER & DESIGNER

Cell: 404-788-8336

www.weblocomotion.com

Skills

HTML5 CSS3 Javascript
Java C++ Python
XAMP Joomla! JSON
Angular 6 React Nodejs

MySQL MongoDB

Photoshop Illustrator Acrobat

Resourceful

Easygoing

Positive

Problem Solving

Great Actitud

References

Available upon request

Certifications

O CCNA Cisco Certified Network AssociateO MCP Microsoft Certified Professional

O Network+ CompTia

O CCNE Certified Novell Engineer - Netware 4.11 - 5.0

Online Education

edx.org

- O University of Bombay Programming Basics in C++
- O Linux Foundation Introduction to Linux
- O MongoDBx Introduction to MongoDB using the MEAN stack
- Web Security Fundamentals KULeuvenX edx.org

udemy.com

- O Anthony Alicea Javascript: Understanding the Weird Parts
- O Anthony Alicea Learn and Understand Nodejs
- O Anthony Alicea Learn and Understand Angularis
- O Infinite Skills White Hacking and Penetration Testing

lynda.com

- O Up and Running with PhoneGap Build
- O Photoshop CS4 for the Web
- O Joommla! 1.5 Essential Training
- O Javascript Essential Training
- O Foundations of Programming Object Oriented Design
- O Foundations of Programming Fundamentals
- O Dreamweaver CS4 Getting Started
- O Android and iOS Apps with Dreamweaver CC and Phonegap

Books

O Object Oriented Programming in C++ - Robert Lafore - 4th Ed